Geno Guerrero









Technical Skills

Front End













Servers





Frameworks





Version Control





Projects

Movie Finder

application for finding top ten current movies. A team project displaying use of an API with a dynamic front end web design.

Dog Meet Dog

Web project with a dating app feel for dog owners. Project displays creative front end design and Google API integration.

Software Developer

As an experienced leader and project lead I have always had the drive to tinker to solve the complex and interesting problems. I write code with a sense of visual design expertise. I am a valued communicator with the skills for both the technical and business professionals. Known as a team player for tackling difficult obstacles, and a constant learner as demanded by the fast paced environment.

Experience



www.leadjammerskates.com

Founder, eCommerce Roller Sports Store

Mar 2008 - Nov 2015

Development and design of the production eCommerce website using the Volusion CMS. With the creative access to the front end design, I spent 7 years creating a successful business and website that attracted repeat customers for several years. Volusion offered customer relationship management where I was able to build strong relationships with customers for several years. *HTML*, *CSS*, *PHP*, *CRM*



www.mensrollerderbyassociation.com

Board of Directors, Public Relations and Secretary

Dec 2010 - Mar 2013

Development and design of the production website used from May 2011 to December 2016. With expertise in front end design as Public Relations Director I was able to put in production a visually appealing project that was used for several years. As Directors we went on to develop and bring to fruition an all volunteer organization to support gender equality and diversity in the community of roller derby. **HTML, CSS, jQuery**

United States Navy Senior Leadership/Management

Jun 1991 – Jul 2011

A leader who lead by example, provided guidance with instruction in dynamic projects and programs in both normal and expeditionary environments. A successful manager and leader who navigated well in large scale collaborative projects from ship's overhauls to detainee operations.

Education



Sept 2016 - Mar 2017

Certification - Foundations of Software Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Certification - Intermediate Software Development in JavaScript

Certification - Advanced Software Development in Full-Stack JavaScript

CODING DO

Dec 2015 - April 2016

Certification - Full Stack JavaScript, MongoDB, ExpressJS, AngularJS, NodeJS

Certification - Full Stack PHP, MySQL, Codelgniter, AJAX, JQuery

Certification - Full Stack Python, MySQL, Flask, AJAX, Django

Certification - Full Stack Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Capybara, PostgreSQL

Olympic College

January 2007 - Dec 2010

Completed credits toward Business Management degree